From gamer to racer.
Gran Turismo is a adventure, action, drama film directed by Neill Blomkamp.
The ultimate wish-fulfillment tale of a teenage Gran Turismo player whose gaming skills won him a
series of Nissan competitions to become an actual professional racecar driver.
Jann Mardenborough, played by Archie Madekwe.
Jack Salter, played by David Harbour.
Danny Moore, played by Orlando Bloom.
Steve Mardenborough, played by Djimon Hounsou.
Matty Davis, played by Darren Barnet.
Audrey, played by Maeve Courtier-Lilley.
Gran Turismo is a 2023 American biographical sports drama film based on the
sim racing video game series developed by Polyphony Digital.
Produced by Columbia Pictures, PlayStation Productions, and 2.0 Entertainment, the film was
directed by Neill Blomkamp from a screenplay by Jason Hall and Zach Baylin.
It depicts a sensationalized account of real life British driver Jann Mardenborough, a
teenage Gran Turismo player who became a professional racing car driver.
The film stars Archie Madekwe as Mardenborough, alongside David Harbour, Orlando
Bloom, Darren Barnet, Geri Halliwell Horner, and Djimon Hounsou.
Development of a film based on Gran Turismo was revealed in July 2013, with Michael
De Luca and Dana Brunetti producing and Alex Tse writing the script.
Joseph Kosinski was set to direct the film in June 2015 from
a new screenplay by Jon and Erich Hoeber.
However, the Kosinski version was no longer moving forward as of February 2018.
In May 2022, it was announced the film was again in development,
with Blomkamp being attached to direct it in June.
The main cast were announced in September 2022, while
other cast additions signed in November.
Filming began in Hungary that month and wrapped in December.
The film score was composed by Lorne Balfe and Andrew Kawczynski.
Gran Turismo premiered at the Circuit de Spa-Francorchamps in Belgium on July 30, 2023, and was
released in the United States on August 25 by Columbia Pictures via Sony Pictures Releasing.
It has grossed $122 million worldwide against its $60 million budget and received mixed reviews from critics, who praised Blomkamp's direction and
racing sequences, but criticized its writing and use of Mardenborough's crash at the Nürburgring Nordschleife as a narrative element.
The film was nominated for "Best Adaptation" at The Game Awards 2023.
The film explores themes of sports, based on true story,
racing, based on video game, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is emotional.